TheChaosLegion
I want to shine on you, and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect, I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time, and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day, I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
～♪
（チャグム）水源が近いんだ
The river source should be close.
ナユグとサグの間にいるのか？
あっ…
Am I halfway between
Nayug and Sagu?
Episode 25
Celebration
Balsa, these flowers
are our last hope.
（タンダ）バルサ
この花が俺たちの最後の希望だ
Can you use these
to save Chagum?
これでチャグムを救えるか？
All right. I'll give it a try.
（バルサ）分かった やってみるよ
必ず チャグムを守ってみせる
I'll do whatever it takes
to protect Chagum.
Herbologist, will those
flowers work for us as well?
（モン）薬草師
その花 我らにも効果はあるか？
（タンダ）ああ
俺が少し まじないをかければ―
Yes. If I cast a
quick spell on them...
恐らく 誰でも
ナユグをのぞけるようになる
...they should allow
anyone to see Nayug.
Give each of us one
of those flowers too.
（ジン）その花を我らにも授けてくれ
（ゼン）たとえ この身が
引き裂かれようとも―
We will take up your cause even if...
...we ourselves are
torn apart in the process. Please!
お主の希望を引き継ごう！ 頼む
I see. Thank you. I was
planning to ask for your help anyway.
（タンダ）そうか ありがとう
俺からも そう頼むつもりだった
All of you, please protect Chagum.
みんなでチャグムを守ってくれ
Many thanks!
かたじけない
We should simply eat them as is?
（ユン）
このまま食べればいいのか？
Yes.
みんな 行こうじゃないか
チャグムが行ったナユグへ！
All right, everyone, let's go!
To Nayug, where
Chagum has gone!
Which way?
（トロガイ）どっちじゃ
That way!
（シュガ）あっちです
（バルサ）もう さっきの卵食いは
見えなくなっちまった
There's no sign of that
other egg-eater from before.
It's no use. I can't see anything.
（ユン）ダメだ 何も見えん
Does the shigu salua
have no effect on me?
俺には
シグ･サルアの効能がないのか？
It's possible that they
don't take effect immediately.
（ジン）そんなに
すぐには効かんのかもしれん
今は薬草師のまじないを信じて
とりあえず皇子に追いつくことが先決
Have faith in the
herbologist's magic.
For now, our top priority is
catching up to Prince Chagum.
What sort of instructions have
you been given by that star reader?
お前たちは あの星読み博士から
どのような指示を受けている？
Master Shuga has told us
that if the need should arise...
シュガ様からは “万が一のときは
精霊の卵のことは忘れて―”
...to forget about the egg and
focus on protecting the prince.
“とにかく 皇子を守れ”と
言われている
I see. In a sense, that
might be the right decision.
なるほど
ある意味 正しい判断かもな
For now, let's gamble
on that decision.
今は その判断に懸けよう
卵が生まれても
チャグムが死んだんじゃ意味がない
Even if the egg is born, it's meaningless
if Chagum is killed in the process.
（タンダ）
なんとか 出血は止まったな…
Looks like the bleeding
has stopped.
It's a living creature, all right.
生き物には違いないが
この世のものとは思えんな
I can't imagine something
like this coming from our world.
（トロガイ）何じゃ それは！
What in the world is that!
Did you get my message?
お前 伝言は受け取ったのか？
Yes. Balsa and those warriors
went ahead to Saanan.
はい
バルサとあの武人たちは
それで先にサアナンに向かいました
そうか さすがは
トロガイ師の教えを受け継ぐ者
I see.
I expected no less from one who
receives Mistress Torogai's teachings.
（トロガイ）うむ…
（タンダ）いや それより…
More importantly...
More importantly, what
happened to this monster?
（トロガイ）それより
どうしたんじゃ？ この化け物は！
How did you defeat it?
どうやって倒したんだい？
I tried eating a shigu salua flower.
シグ･サルアの花を食べてみたんです
I discovered that the flower's
pollen acts as a medium...
花の蜜が触媒となり―
我々でもナユグに干渉できることが
分かりました
...and that allows us humans
to interact with Nayug.
Ah, I see...
なるほど でかした！ 弟子よ
Well done, pupil of mine!
So, do you have any
more of those flowers?
で その花は まだあるのか？
I'm sorry. But I gave all of them
to Balsa and the others.
残念ながら バルサたちに
全部 渡してしまいました
Damn...
なんと…
Young as you are, you might live
to see another rebirth of the spirit...
お前の年なら もう一度
精霊の生まれ変わりを見られるが―
...but this was my last chance.
わしは
これが最後の機会だったのに…
Come on, this was
my last chance too.
（タンダ）
俺だって これが最後ですよ
Mistress Torogai,
we should make haste as well.
（シュガ）トロガイ師
我々も先を急ぎましょう
Right now, protecting the prince is...
とにかく 今は皇子を
Don't be in such a hurry.
（トロガイ）そう慌てるな
夜明けまでは食われまい
He won't be eaten until dawn.
師匠 あの熊…
Mistress, that bear...
ああ どうやら…
I see it. It's also carrying a...
ラルンガ？
A Rarunga?
（トロガイ）見えるのか？
（タンダ）はい
You can see it?
Yes.
Was that a...
あれは…
ああ
恐らく ニュンガ･ロ･イムの卵だ
Yes, it was probably
a Nyunga Ro lm egg.
チャグムの他にも
いるだろうとは思っていたが…
I suspected that there might
be others besides Chagum.
Being culled like that is probably
part of the natural order.
ああやって とう汰されていくのが
大自然の摂理なんじゃろう
Then, Chagum might also...
（タンダ）じゃあ チャグムも？
（トロガイ）そうだね―
Right, he might not be safe
until daybreak after all.
明け方まで安心ってことでも
ないようじゃな
急ぐぞ 星読み博士！
We need to hurry, star reader!
Mistress, take me with you!
（タンダ）
師匠 俺も連れていってください
（シュガ）そうです 彼も一緒に…
Yes, we should take him too.
Oh, all right.
（トロガイ）しかたないね
じゃあ お前が馬に乗りな
You get on the horse, then!
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
（チャグム）
不思議だ まるで寒くない
It's strange. I'm not cold at all...
So this is Saanan...
ここが サアナン…
えっ… そろそろ生まれるのか？
Are you ready to be born, then?
バルサ
Balsa!
Balsa...
バルサ…
But I...
でも 俺は…
チャグム！ そこを動くんじゃないよ
Chagum! Stay where you are!
Balsa...
バルサ
Your Highness!
皇子！
短槍(たんそう)使い 先に行け！
Spear-wielder, you go on ahead!
分かった
なんとか食い止めてくれ
Right! Do what you
can to hold it off!
（バルサ）チャグム！
Chagum!
（チャグム）バルサ！
Balsa!
You're all right!
無事だったんだね
Balsa, I knew you
would come for me.
（チャグム）バルサ
必ず来てくれると思ってた
信じてたよ バルサ
I always had faith in you, Balsa.
Sune! Shoot this!
スン！ これを撃て
（スン）やったか？
Did I get it?
That's a...
あれは…
In Nayug, this area is under water.
ナユグでは水の中なんだ
師匠
Teacher, this area appears
to be underwater in Nayug.
どうやら ここは
ナユグでは水の中のようです
Let's find a way up to
the top of those cliffs.
いったん 崖の上に上がりましょう
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Have we done it?
（ジン）やったか？
バルサ！ チャグム！
Balsa! Chagum!
えっ… 皇子が見えるのか？
どこに？
You can see the prince?
Where is he?
（トロガイ）
くそっ わしにも見えんぞ
Damn, I can't see them, either.
To think my student can
see something that I can't...
弟子に見えるものが見えんとは…
How can this be?
なんたること…
私の知る 見ている世界とは
せいぜい この世の半分
The world I know, the world I see...
is it no more than half of this world?
いや 万分の一に過ぎんのか…
No, one ten-thousandth?
Anyway, let's hurry.
とにかく急ぎましょう
ダメだ！
ラルンガを殺してはいけない…
No! You mustn't kill the Rarunga!
What's the matter, Chagum?
どうした チャグム？
You want to come out?
生まれたいのか…
やはり ラルンガに
俺が引き裂かれなくちゃ―
You can't come out unless
I'm torn apart by the Rarunga?
お前は出てこられないのか…
まいったね こればっかりは
私じゃ どうすることも…
I hate this... This is something that
I can't do anything to help with.
Mistress, I'll go on ahead!
師匠 先に行きます
（モン）ええい！
There are more?
まだいるのか？
Commander, I'm
almost out of arrows.
（スン）お頭 もう矢が…
We don't have much oil left, either.
（ヒョク）油も もう残り少ない…
伝説の八武人(はちぶじん)は この状況を
三日三晩しのいだという
The Warriors Eight of legend...
...fought on in this situation
for three days and nights.
We may run out of oil,
but thanks to the herbalist...
油が尽きようが
薬草師のおかげで―
...we can now confront
these Nayug creatures in battle.
ナユグのモノと
切り結べるようになったのだ
たとえ この身が尽きようと
剣一本で戦い抜くのみ！
Even if all we have left are our swords,
we shall fight to the death!
The commander is right!
お頭の言うとおりだ
我らにも できぬはずはない！
We can do this!
Spear-wielder, take the prince and
flee from here while we hold them off!
短槍使い！
皇子を連れて
今のうちに ここを離れよ！
まずは皇子を逃がすことが先決！
His escape is our top priority!
分かった
Understood. Chagum, hang on.
We're getting away from here.
チャグム しっかりしな
ここを離れるんだよ
ダメだよ ダメなんだ バルサ
I can't... I can't leave, Balsa.
卵は ここに残りたがっている
The egg wants to stay here.
ここで今日 生まれなかったら―
If it isn't born here today,
it's going to die inside of me.
卵は俺の中で死んでしまうんだ
I can't let that happen!
The egg wants to be born here!
それじゃダメなんだ！
卵は
ここで生まれたがっているんだ！
行け！ 短槍使い 早く！
Go, Spear-wielder! Hurry!
Sune!
スン！ えいっ
（モン）ええい！
バルサ 俺も まだ生きたいよ
Balsa, I still want to live too.
But I'm going to put
myself in fate's hands.
でも 俺は運命に身を委ねる
I can't live if it means
sacrificing your lives...
俺は みんなの犠牲の上に
生きることも―
...or sacrificing
Yogo's million citizens.
ヨゴ百万の民を
犠牲にすることもできない
So please, stop fighting!
I'll do what has to be done!
だから もう これ以上
戦うのはやめてくれ
俺は俺にしかできないことをやる
チャグム…
Chagum...
（モン）ええい！
Your Highness!
皇子！ うっ…
（ジン）
皇子！ 我らのことは気にせず―
Your Highness, don't concern
yourselves about us. Just run!
早く逃げて… くっ…
Everyone...
みんな…
（バルサ）タンダ！
Tanda!
It looks like he's
crossed over into Nayug.
ナユグに行ったようだね…
Balsa!
（タンダ）バルサ！
心配するな チャグム
Don't worry, Chagum!
I can extract the egg using
a spell I learned from Torogai.
師匠に聞いた呪術で
精霊の卵は取り出せる
We need to get Chagum
to someplace safe first.
だから まずはチャグムを安全な所に
You mean it?
本当かい？
Yes. From what the star reader says,
there's a record of a magic weaver...
ああ 星読み博士の話でも
200年前 同じ試みをして―
...200 years ago who made the
same attempt and nearly succeeded.
もう少しのところまで
いった記述があるそうだ
あんたを信じるよ チャグムを頼む
I'll take your word for it.
Keep an eye on Chagum for me!
It's all right. There's nothing
to worry about, Chagum!
大丈夫だ 何も心配するな チャグム
（モン）ええい！
トロガイ師 なんとか 私たちに
できることはないのですか？
Torogai, is there
nothing that we can do?
ない
Nothing. Just sit quietly
and pray for the sun to rise.
黙って朝日が昇るのを祈れ
チャグム 頼む 動いてくれ！
Please, Chagum,
you have to move!
How many of these
things are there?
（バルサ）いったい 何匹いるんだ？
（ジン）きりがないぞ
There's no end to them!
トロガイ師…
Torogai?
They seem to be fighting
a huge number of Rarunga.
どうやら ものすごい数の
ラルンガと戦っているようだ
くそっ！
Damn!
しかたないね
I suppose I'll go too...
（バルサ）やっ！
（モン）みんな 短槍使いに続け！
Everyone, follow the
spear-wielder's lead!
（モン）ええい！
バルサ！
Balsa!
（モン）朝日！
The morning sun?
（バルサ）
そうか サグの夜が明けたのか…
I get it. The sun must
have come up in Sag...
（ジン）助かったのか？
We made it?
あっ… 皇子！
Your Highness?
Balsa...
バルサ
（トロガイ）急げ
Hurry!
Torogai!
（タンダ）師匠！
If we don't hurry, Nayug and
Sagu will separate completely.
早くしないと
ナユグとサグが完全に離れてしまう
Right.
（タンダ）はい！
バルサ 手を貸してくれ
Balsa, give me a hand.
いいか
Listen...
Gently reach inside.
このまま そっと手を差し入れろ
（チャグム）痛いよ！ 痛い…
It hurts!
大丈夫
そのまま そっと卵に触れるんだ
It's all right.
Gently take hold of the egg.
（チャグム）痛いよ！
うわああーっ！
It hurts!
Well? Did you find it?
どうじゃ？ あったか？
うう… 痛いよ
It hurts!
それが卵？
That is the egg?
無事 生まれたんだね
You were safely born, weren't you?
“生きたい 生きたい”っていう
願いが かなったんだね
Your wish to live came true.
やりおったな タンダ バルサよ
You've done it, Tanda, Balsa.
（タンダ）はい
Yes.
Balsa, let me see the egg too.
バルサ… 俺にも卵を…
You were very brave...
よく生まれてきてくれた
温かい…
It's warm.
Now, the next order of business...
さて あとは…
Yes, the nahji.
ナージ… ですね
Yes. If no nahji come, that
unprotected egg will probably die soon.
ああ あれが来なければ―
むき出しの卵は
すぐに死んでしまうだろうからね
ナージ！
Nahji!
Nahji have come!
ナージが来おった！
You're right! It's nahji!
確かに… ナージ！
They're flying off without seeing us.
気付かず行ってしまうぞ…
大丈夫 気付く
It's all right. They'll see us.
It's coming back!
戻ってくるぞ
チャグム どうすればいい？
Chagum, what should we do now?
Throw the egg high into the sky,
and the nahji will take it in its beak.
空高く卵を投げれば
ナージがくわえていってくれる
（トロガイ）今頃 来おったか…
Now they show up...
そうですね
Indeed... But now we can
give him a return worthy of a king.
でも これで 王の帰還に
華を添えることができます
終わったんだ 運命との戦いが…
It's all over. My fight
against destiny is finally over...
As I sat huddled and alone, holding back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were, at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong." I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in, I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell my dear one, "Thank you."
At the top of my lungs, again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes, human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence of the one that I hold dear.
～♪
Chagum and Balsa have
entrusted the egg to the nahji.
What fate awaits them
now that it is all over?
The final episode, "Departure."
Episode 26
Departure
I will never forget you.